Rajarajan Packianathan (raj)

FRONT END UI LEAD / PROGRAMMER



letsthinkbetter@gmail.com

4 01-May-1989

Bengaluru



About Me

I am a strong front end web programmer with excellent javascript and web programming skills.

My current forte is Angular and experienced in numerous projects involving various front end frameworks such as Rxjs, Redux (ngRx), React JS etc. Proficient in Javascript Design Patterns and pay utmost importance to the architectural decisions and design patterns applied to each and every part of the application code.

Conducted numerous tech sessions on various web stack technologies to guide and help budding programmers to reach the desired expertise.

Primary Skills

Angular	****
JAVASCRIPT	****
Javascript Design Patterns	***
Typescript/ES6	****
RxJs Observables	****
REDUX (NGRX)	****
HTML, CSS	***
REACT JS	★★☆☆☆
BACKBONE JS	★★☆☆☆

Technologies

HTML, CSS, Sass, JQUERY

JAVASCRIPT, TYPESCRIPT, ANGULAR + NATIVESCRIPT

ANGULAR (2+), ANGULAR JS, ANGULAR + REDUX

UNIT TESTS WITH JASMINE

UI e2e test automations with Puppeter

GULP. WEBPACK

Nodejs + Express

RESPONSIVE WEB DESIGN

Education

B.E. Computer Science

Work Experience

10 Years, 3 Months

SIEMENS ... Healthineers

UI PROGRAMMER / LEAD, UI COMMUNITY LEAD

Siemens Healthineers Pvt Ltd

Jul 2018 - Present

Revamped Siemens medical applications and brought in the latest technologies and standards into their application suites. Rewrote, Angular js app to Angular v7 (now in v11) and established industry's best practices and standards.

Solely, written many utility libraries such as XLSX exporter, SVG graphs, communication brokers to serve as common shared package for large suites of applications. Again, individually written the UI controls library (including feature rich data grid tables, date range pickers etc.) as reusable components based on Siemens UX style guides for wider use in suites of applications. Built a UI e2e test library that runs on top of google's puppeteer, with the purpose to simplify the automation process and bring ease of use and convenience to programmers of varying skills.

Conduct and lead the 'Front end community of practices' for wider Siemens projects and divisions, with the goal to address topics, questions and discussions surrounding the UI Web technology stack.

FRONT END UI PROGRAMMER / CONSULTANT Infosys Ltd.

Infosys

Oct 2017 - Jul 2018

Developed applications using Angular, RXJS and Redux for asset management dashboard for Dell. Designed and developed custom view-model* and Observables frameworks for a specific application that encouraged in-house frameworks over popular UI frameworks.

Developed a cafeteria application to order food using Angular + Nativescript (android and Web) as side project during spare time.

TECHNICAL LEAD / PROGRAMMER

Tech Mahindra

Tech Mahindra Ltd.

Mar 2015 - Oct 2017

Designed and developed applications in React JS, Angular (2+), RXJS and Backbone JS.

Built and enhanced order management application using React Js.

Developed an Service management and SR tracking application for Telia a

telecom company using Angular. Involved in couple of POCs with primary focus on Javascript and responsive web layouts.

TEAM LEAD

Estuate Pvt. Ltd.

Jan 2011 - Mar 2015

Built various web applications using Javascript, Backbone JS, Angular JS 1.x, HTML, CSS, Jquery while paying importance to Design Patterns.